# MOHAMED ANSAF

20A, AMI Naina Marikkar St, Spill Road, Puttalam 61300, Sri Lanka Email: ansafsah@gmail.com | Mobile: +94 77 857 6936 | Skype: ansafsah

### **Personal Statement**

A passionate, software engineer professional with more than 7 years of hands-on experience on JavaScript, PHP, Java and Mobile application developments with covering multiple stacks, Excellent knowledge on keeping atop of new developments within the industry and can adopt quickly to new technologies.

#### Skills

DevOps: Jenkins, Spinnaker, Argo CD, AWS EC2

Programming: JavaScript, PHP, Java

Stacks: HTML, CSS/SCSS, TypeScript, Angular (6, 7, 12 & 13), ES5/ES6, Spring boot, Laravel 3,

Symfony (2 & 3), Ionic 2, Cordova, MySQL, Mongo DB, Eloquent, JPA, Doctrine,

Hibernate

Tools: Bash, Git, Bitbucket, JIRA, GitHub, GitLab, Trello

Languages: English, Tamil

## **Professional Experience**

#### Cloud Solutions International Pvt Ltd.

Colombo, Sri Lanka Jul 2022 – Current

Senior Software Engineer

- Worked as senior role with Tech leads and Architects to design and implement micro frontend architecture to existing Angular live projects.
- Several R&Ds done for micro frontend with Angular module federation library, which used to configure, build remote and host applications.
- Optimized common library was developed to load micro frontend exposed components into the view dynamically.
- Implemented, configured shared state management store between micro frontend applications with NgRx
- Managed junior developers in a team, perform technical discussions, assign tasks.
- Performed code reviews and merging pull requests.

#### Software Engineer

Feb 2020 – Jul 2022

- Worked on some crucial features of the enterprise applications used by the largest hospitals in middle east regions, also having extensive knowledge in healthcare domains.
- Worked on R&D projects to develop form designer with layout customization using Gridster library.
- Developed optimized runtime library for form designer with the use of caching and memoizing.
- Maintained, prepared monthly production release branches in private Bitbucket repositories.
- Created Docker build images using Jenkins and deployed with Spinnaker or Argo CD.

- Experienced on Again software development frameworks such as Sprint and Kanban.
- Daily scrum, sprint planning, explaining tasks and showing short demo of each completed tasks. in sprint review and discussing sprint retrospectives.

#### Associate Software Engineer

Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

- Worked on major role of converting existing module components to Angular libraries which used across many teams.
- Adding requested features for common libraries
- Experienced in resolving prod build issues while converting modules into libraries.
- Managed versions and published libraries followed by Sementic versioning best practices.
- Writing markdown documentations and providing support for all teams.

#### **Imara Software Solutions Pvt Ltd**

Sri Lanka

Full Stack Software Developer

Sep 2018 – Jul 2019

- Worked on Laravel projects, the user portal to customize ebay descriptions using Ebay REST APIs.
- Deployments, schedule cron jobs on Digital Ocean private hosts.
- Designed and built a JavaScript project, set coordinates, draw lines, marker on Leaflet.js maps from imported CSV files.

#### Freelancing - Remote

United States

Full Stack Software Developer

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

- Designed, developed a PHP MVC Laravel project with Rest API for Parking lot management system.
- Developed separate mobile applications for admin and other users using Ionic 2 and Rest API integrations.
- Integration of native Cordova plugins to Ionic mobile apps such as OpenALPR etc.
- Integrated SMS notification service using Nexmo API.
- Developed an Auth server, provide JWT tokens and CURD operations with REST APIs with Larayel.
- Developed a socket server for live chat feature on mobile application using Node.js.
- Payment gateway integrations, PayPal Express checkout and recurring payments using PayPal Rest API and SDK.
- Deployment of Laravel applications on AWS EC2 Linux instance using SSH.

Adsfly.lk Sri Lanka

Full Stack Software Developer

Aug 2016 - Sep 2018

- Designed and developed an PHP MVC project, Inventory management system for Pharmacies using Laravel, MySQL and Eloquent.
- WordPress plugin development such as overriding Woo-commerce templates, build plugins to customize navigation menu and styles.
- Projects maintained on version management systems, GitLab and GitHub.
- Developed REST APIs with Laravel framework for Ionic mobile apps.
- Websites maintained, deployed on private web hosting.

#### Internship

- Designed web pages for hotel booking website using HTML and CSS.
- Designed, developed a project for money transfer and currency exchange with admin panel using PHP Symfony framework, MySQL and Doctrine ORM.

# **Education**

### University of Colombo, Sri Lanka Bachelor's degree in Information Technology

Mar 2017 - Jun 2021

## Links

Github: https://github.com/ansafans

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ansafans/

Stack overflow: <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/8482039/ansaf-ans">https://stackoverflow.com/users/8482039/ansaf-ans</a>

More references to be provided upon request.